S. Nicole Clevenger

Business Analyst | Operational & Logistic Analysts | Data Analyst

Nashville Metropolitan Area 615-815-4995

<u>snicole.clevenger@gmail.com</u>
<u>LinkedIn/snicoleclevenger</u>
GitHub: SNClevTN

My journey towards data

Throughout my life I have been called observant, an adventurous go-getter,

driven, and a skilled professional. I have thrived in each role to the best of my ability simply because I am willing to learn and glean wisdom from researching on my own, collaborating with teammates, clients, and others willing to teach me. I am excited to merge the experience I have with the power of data; I am beginning to see the puzzle pieces coming together.

Skills

PostgreSQL | Tableau | PowerBI | Python | Juypter Notebooks | GitHub | Excel

Data Analytics Experience

January 2021 - Present

Nashville Software School / Nashville, TN

Data Analytics Apprentice

NSS prepares adults with aptitude, motivation, and drive for careers in multiple software development fields.

- Cyber Crime Victim report 2015-2020 <u>GitHub-Cyber Crime IC3</u>
 Used Excel for cleaning and formatting public data from PDFs on the IC3 FBI's website. Each PDF contains data for the specific year and is presented differently each year. I have combined this data in Excel and used Tableau to visualize how age, type of crimes, and the amount of money loss over 5 years has changed over time.
- Nashville monthly search <u>GitHub-Search</u>
 Apply descriptive statistic, logical, and conditional functions using Excel to navigate a spreadsheet of public data.
- Nashville City Cemetery marketing campaign <u>GitHub-NCC</u>
 I created marketing material with excel visualizations to help gain the interest of the public to visit the cemetery. In Excel I organized, cleaned, and formulated patterns using incomplete and poorly entered data to achieve this goal for the client. I researched the top type of death known as consumption to complete the pamphlet.
- Texas Child Protection Agent Deficiencies in foster care agencies <u>GitHub -TX</u>

 I researched a public raw dataset to cleanup in SQL. Power BI is exclusively used to create visualizations to report the findings on the top foster care agencies in Texas during 2015 who may be abusing the system.
- Zoo Who is coming after you? <u>GitHub-Zoo</u>

This is an individual project to create a visualization of a public dataset to explore what animals are venomous in zoos. This visualization will help preppers stay safe during the apocalypse.

Work Experience

May 2017 - March 2018

Operations Manager / BC7, East Nashville, TN

BC7 is a well-established general contractor in Nashville specializing in renovating historical homes.

- Ensured standard operating procedures were followed to set proper expectations for improved workflow.
- Estimate renovation projects and assist in presenting to clients.
- Gauged client's budgets to account payables and oversaw accounting processes.
- Administrative assistant to owner for business development opportunities to expand.

Additional Experience

October 2014 - January 2017

Process Manager & Coordinator / Response Team 1, Brentwood, TN

RT1 was a large corporate restoration company who acquired an apartment complex renovation company.

- Coordinated logistics to assist and anticipate issues for Project Managers in TN and NC.
- Verify and enter account payables to appropriate funds to contractors.
- Procure and maintain vendor and contractor relationships.

October 2012 - March 2015

AutoCAD Independent Consultant / Productive CAD Services, Smyrna, TN

As an independent consultant I traveled to hospitals around the country to provide AutoCAD services as needed.

- Anticipated solutions for clients before issues arose by implementing and using Fire Safety Codes for Hospitals.
- Provided up to date construction plans to the facility.
- Updated and collaborated with an architect and designer to freshen up older home designs.

May 2008 - October 2012

AutoCAD Support Specialist / SSR Inc., Nashville, TN

SSR Inc. is an Engineer Firm with its core business based on Hospital construction and maintenance.

- Created detail-oriented drawings for government compliancy reports.
- Assisted and anticipated issues for clients and consultants across the country.
- Learned and trained software to apply Life Safety codes during field inspections.
- Provided professional and responsive customer service.

Education

January 2021 - April 2021

Nashville Software School / Nashville, TN

Full-time Data Analytics Bootcamp

Purdue University / West Lafayette, IN

Bachelor of Science in Computer Graphics Design Technology